<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Istanbul Guide</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to Istanbul</string>

    <string name="welcome_text">Istanbul, a fascinating city built on two Continents, divided by the Bosphorus Strait. This is one of the greatest cities in the world where you can see a modern western city combined with a traditional eastern city, it\'s a melting pot of many civilizations and different people. Istanbul was also announced by the European Union as the 2010 European Capital of Culture.\n\nFrom the foundation of Byzantium in the 7th century BC until today, Istanbul held always an important role in the history of humanity in this part of the world. Everybody wanted to gain control of this area because of its strategic location; Empires were born here on the ashes of previous ones.
\n\nSince the Republic in 1923, Istanbul continued to grow and today it boosted its population over 14 million people living in this spread out city. This makes Istanbul the largest city of Turkey and one of the biggest cities in the world.</string>

    <string name="start_trip">Press Anywhere to Start</string>
    
    <string name="touristic_places">Touristic Places</string>
    <string name="restaurants">Eating Places</string>
    <string name="hotels">Hotels</string>
    <string name="fun_places">Fun Places</string>
    <string name="famous_location">Famous Locations</string>

    <!-- FunPlacesFragment's data -->
    <string name="galata_bridge">Galata Bridge</string>
    <string name="galata_bridge_info">Spanning the Golden Horn, Istanbul’s iconic Galata Bridge is a top spot for fishing. Locals, especially men, like to come here to fish for fun and sometimes to earn money.</string>
    <string name="miniatürk">Miniatürk</string>
    <string name="miniatürk_info">This open-air park contains 126 miniature replicas of historic Turkish monuments. It’s a great place for families as well as for those who don’t have time to see all of Istanbul’s famous sites.</string>
    <string name="istanbul_toy_museum">Istanbul Toy Museum</string>
    <string name="istanbul_toy_museum_info">İstanbul Oyuncak Müzesi houses a huge collection of toys from over 40 countries. You’ll see many of the world’s most popular playthings dating from the 1700s right up to the present day. It’s a fascinating experience for children and adults alike.</string>
    <string name="rahmi_koc_museum">Rahmi Koc Museum</string>
    <string name="rahmi_koc_museum_info">This glorious museum is dedicated to the history of transport, industry and communications. It houses a fantastic collection of objects highlighting Turkey’s industrial past.</string>
    <string name="ortaköy_square">Ortaköy Square</string>
    <string name="ortaköy_square_info">This popular square is full of fancy waterfront cafés, restaurants, bars and clubs. Young locals often come here to smoke “nargile” (Turkish water pipes) and play backgammon and card games. Many people also come here to eat “kumpir” (stuffed baked potatoes).</string>

    <!-- HotelFragment's data -->
    <string name="four_season_hotel">Four Seasons Hotel</string>
    <string name="four_season_hotel_info">First time visitors to Turkey\'s most populated city will be hard-pressed to find a hotel with a better address than the Four Seasons Hotel at Sultanahmet. That\'s because Istanbul\'s biggest attractions, including the Hagia Sophia and the Blue Mosque, are a stone\'s throw from the property. Though the hotel\'s address was a major standout for recent guests, the property\'s attentive staff and amenities also impressed. Multilingual concierges are at your beck and call 24 hours a day and babysitting services can be arranged with as little as three hours\' notice (sometimes even less). Standard rooms here are spacious, measuring between 592 to 645 square feet, and feature traditional Turkish decor, including handwoven Turkish kilims, alongside modern amenities like free Wi-Fi, espresso machines and bathrooms with both a television and deep soaking tub. There are plenty of dining options nearby, but guests say a drink on the A'YA Rooftop Lounge, which overlooks both the Hagia Sophia and Blue Mosque, simply cannot be skipped. And if you're in need of some additional downtime, the hotel offers spa services and a fitness facility to help you recharge.</string>
    <string name="tomtom_suites">TomTom Suites</string>
    <string name="tomtom_suites_info">This boutique hotel in Istanbul is all about attention to detail. That\'s because Tomtom Suites only has 20 rooms, leaving plenty of extra room for personalized service. And guests were able to pick up on this strategy right away. Lodgers loved staff\'s eagerness to provide recommendations and appreciated that any and all inquiries were met with a smile. The large rooms were also a standout, with standard suites starting at 474 square feet. Pillow menus, LCD TVs with DVD players, Nespresso coffee machines, loaner iPads, homemade chocolates and minibars are just a few of the in-room amenities you can expect to take advantage of during your stay. The hotel also has 24-hour concierge, in-room spa and express checkout services, as well as a complimentary breakfast buffet. In their downtime, guests can brush up on their knowledge of the city and Turkey itself at the on-site library, or grab a bite to eat at Chef Restaurant Nicole, which serves Mediterranean dishes both indoors and outside on a terrace overlooking the old town. Outside, guests can wander the historical area of Galata and Pera or take the metro, located just a couple blocks away, to nearby top attractions such as the Blue Mosque and Hagia Sophia. What's more, this property is one of the more affordable options on the Best Hotels in Europe ranking.</string>
    <string name="sirkeci_mansion">Sirkeci Mansion</string>
    <string name="sirkeci_mansion_info">If you want to learn about Turkish history and culture while staying in Istanbul, then consider staying at Sirkeci Mansion. Just steps from the Topkapi Palace Museum and the Istanbul Archaeological Museums, this family-owned property prides itself on offering immersive experiences like free Turkish cooking classes and weekly guided walks through the city. Additionally, you\'ll have access to complimentary meze (Turkish appetizers) in the hotel\'s living room, Turkish baths and Neyzade Restaurant, which serves gourmet regional cuisine. A fitness center, a heated swimming pool and a sauna are also available on-site. When it's time to rest, retreat to one of the property's 32 guest rooms, which feature hardwood floors, floral fabric accents and at least 194 square feet of space. Standard amenities include coffee and tea makers, minibars and free Wi-Fi access. Previous guests praised Sirkeci Mansion's spacious and well-equipped rooms, but many were even more impressed with the hotel's outstanding staff and central location.</string>
    <string name="kempinski_hotel">Kempinski Hotel</string>
    <string name="kempinski_hotel_info">If you want to be treated like royalty while enjoying picturesque views of the Bosphorus, consider staying at Çiragan Palace Kempinski Istanbul. This former Ottoman Empire palace participates in The Leading Hotels of the World\'s Leaders Club loyalty program and can be found between Istanbul\'s Besiktas and Ortakoy neighborhoods. The hotel boasts 313 accommodations with traditional Turkish decor, flat-screen TVs, minibars and balconies. Standard rooms and select suites overlook Yildiz Park, while other accommodations feature sea vistas. For even more luxury and space, reserve one of the hotel\'s Exclusive Palace Suites, which have up to three bedrooms and include perks like butler service and kitchenettes. Or, pamper yourself at the on-site spa. In addition to various treatments, the facility houses a hammam, a fitness center, a sauna and an outdoor infinity pool (one of the world's most beautiful). The hotel also has a 24-hour business center, multiple boutiques, three restaurants and Le Fumoir, where cocktails and hookah service are offered daily. Previous guests raved about this property's \"breathtaking\" design, \"delicious\" breakfasts and \"very courteous\" staff, saying that their stays were \"simply amazing\" and well worth the expensive room rates. Plus, several top attractions – including Taksim Square and Dolmabahçe Palace – sit less than 3 miles away."</string>
    <string name="hotel_sultania">Hotel Sultania</string>
    <string name="hotel_sultania_info">According to previous visitors, Hotel Sultania lives up to its promise of making each guest \"feel like a sultan.\" Travelers loved this Istanbul property\'s helpful staff, as well as the complimentary tea and Turkish Delight candies provided at check-in. For more substantial meals, the hotel offers four options: the casual Sultania Restaurant, Olive Anatolian Restaurant (a Mediterranean-inspired fine dining establishment), a breakfast buffet and 24-hour room service. All of the cuisine served on-site received rave reviews from past diners. After satiating your appetite, enjoy a massage at the spa, break a sweat in the fitness center, take a dip in one of two pools or unwind in the hammam or sauna. Then, retreat to your clean and well-appointed room, which offers Ottoman-inspired decor, a satellite TV, free Wi-Fi access and a minibar. Some upgraded spaces also have attached outdoor spaces or private hammams. If you\'re traveling with kids, you'll have access to additional perks, such as baby cots and child-sized bathrobes, plus discounted admissions at family-friendly attractions like Vialand theme park and Istanbul Aquarium if you book directly through the hotel's website. Other sights, including the Blue Mosque, the Basilica Cistern and the Hagia Sophia Museum, can be found within walking distance of the hotel.</string>
    <string name="levni_hotel">Levni Hotel &amp; Spa</string>
    <string name="levni_hotel_info">Former guests raved about Levni Hotel &amp; Spa\'s attentive staff and clean, comfortable accommodations. All of the hotel\'s 75 guest rooms are individually appointed and have accent walls or tufted headboards, and patterned carpets or hardwood floors. Standard rooms boast work desks, minibars, flat-screen TVs and walk-in showers or bathtubs. And in the hotel\'s largest accommodation, the Bosphorus Suit Room, you\'ll find a Jacuzzi, a dressing room and a balcony with city and sea views. No matter which accommodation you choose, you\'ll have access to multiple meeting rooms, a business center, an indoor swimming pool, a hammam and a gym. Past travelers also recommended eating breakfast at the on-site restaurant, which they said offers a good selection of hot and cold items on its buffet, including gluten-free and vegetarian options. When you're ready to explore Istanbul, walk to nearby top attractions like the Basilica Cistern, the Blue Mosque and the Grand Bazaar. While most recent guests reported a satisfactory stay, some said they encountered minor issues like inadequate soundproofing and malfunctioning air-conditioning units."</string>

    <!-- RestaurantFragment's data -->
    <string name="ulus_29">Ulus 29</string>
    <string name="ulus_29_info">Opened in 1993, Ulus 29 is the perfect place to view Bosphorus and the bridges of Istanbul from the restaurant’s terraces in the summer. Ulus 29 centers on gastronomic concepts with traditional cooking methods to offer regional cuisine with seasonal freshness. The restaurant makes its own dry-aged meats as well as ice cream and pasta for an authentic experience when searching for where to eat in Istanbul. Opt for gastronomy-focused dishes, classic Turkish fare or sushi. A wine list of roughly 4,500 bottles includes labels  Enjoy cocktails at the Teras Bar, or choose a lively evening at the Ulus Club 29 to dance along to international DJs on the weekends.</string>
    <string name="rana">Râna</string>
    <string name="rana_info">At Râna, formerly known as Topaz, the best of Mediterranean and Ottoman cuisine come together. Overlooking the Bosphorus, the serene atmosphere of Râna recalls the stone it is named after in its geometric design that is complemented by modern decor. The restaurant offers two tasting menus: modern and traditional. The first comprises innovative dishes like goose liver terrine with cranberry marmalade and walnut, while the latter includes classics like Turkish ravioli with beef and strained yogurt. Râna’s wine list has acquired national recognition with an award from local magazine Gusto and the staff is happy to provide pairings on request.</string>
    <string name="baynan">Baynan</string>
    <string name="baynan_info">With Istanbul wedged between Eastern and Western influences, Banyan’s motto of “food for the soul” describes the Asian fusion fare it serves. Healthy cuisine with Asian roots is savored on the top floor of a historical building, offering striking views of the city below. Dishes like Sichuan pepper steak, duck satay and dim sum are just a few of the options on order to be enjoyed with tea, fresh juice or a cocktail. Whether dining indoors or outdoors, the lights of surrounding Istanbul are sure to dazzle from this local favorite.</string>
    <string name="maiden_tower">Maiden\'s Tower Restaurant</string>
    <string name="maiden_tower_info">The signature of Istanbul, Maiden’s Tower stands proudly in the intersection of the Bosphorus where the two continents of Asia and Europe meet. The tower’s history stretches back 2,500 years, with a wealth of legends surrounding its place in this extraordinary city. Now the tower serves as a café and restaurant, attracting guests from near and far for a romantic meal, business engagement, or even a wedding. With delicious breakfasts and international lunch and dinner menus, Maiden’s Tower can be enjoyed at any time of day. Live music and a friendly mood will accompany your meal, and with the Bosphorus on all sides, the views are magical. Indoors in the winter or outdoors in the summer, for a truly bespoke experience, ask for the exclusive booking options and enjoy Maiden’s Tower in unique style.</string>
    <string name="feriye_palace">Feriye Palace</string>
    <string name="feriye_palace_info">Once an Ottoman police station, Feriye’s building is a rare example of 19th-century classical Ottoman architecture. An advocate for Turkish gastronomy, Feriye holds regular seminars and special food presentations. The restaurant draws on Ottoman cooking techniques from the 12th to 19th century and includes such delicacies as spicy cured beef and manti (filled dough pockets). Feriye can host a wide range of events: the à la carte restaurant caters for cocktail parties and sit-down dinners, and in summer the huge terrace can accommodate up to 2,000 guests."</string>

    <!-- TouristLocationFragment's data -->
    <string name="hagia_sophia">Hagia Sophia Museum</string>
    <string name="hagia_sophia_info">Once a church, then a mosque and now it is a museum. This more than a thousand year old work of art will attract you in. Not to give any spoilers, don’t forget to make a wish inside.</string>
    <string name="topkapi_palace">Topkapi Palace</string>
    <string name="topkapi_palace_info">It was once the home of emperors of 3 continents. It is a must-see for everyone as it homes a great view of Istanbul, traces of hundreds of years of history and priceless treasures.</string>
    <string name="blue_mosque">Blue(Sultan Ahmed) Mosque</string>
    <string name="blue_mosque_info">Half thousand year old mosque, built by Mehmet Agha (last student of architech Sinan) welcomes millions of tourists every year. Fine tiles brought by Iznik make it look bluer that it is.</string>
    <string name="dolmabahce_palace">Dolmabahce Palace Museum</string>
    <string name="dolmabahce_palace_info">Dolmabahçe Palace was the administrative center of the Ottoman Empire for almost a century, then it served as the house of Mustafa Kemal Ataturk, founder of the Turkish Republic.</string>
    <string name="grand_bazaar">Grand Bazaar</string>
    <string name="grand_bazaar_info">It’s one of the largest and oldest markets in the world. It’s just like shopping in those old movies. Test your bargaining skills in there and shop for fantastic gifts and souvenirs.</string>
    <string name="galata_tower">Galata Tower</string>
    <string name="galata_tower_info">The first man ever to fly with wings, Hezarfen, jumped off Galata Tower and flew all the way to the Asian side of Istanbul. The Tower has a fantastic 360° Istanbul view and will bring you amazing shots.</string>
    <string name="basilica_cistern">Basicila Cistern</string>
    <string name="basilica_cistern_info">Used as one of the film locations for James Bond’s From Russia with Love, this place was originally a basilica and was later converted to a cistern in order to provide water to the Great Palace of Constantinople.</string>

</resources>